

# Stamatis Choudalakis, Ms.C (University of Athens).

PhD candidate in Medical School, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens,

Greece

Email: st.xoud@gmail.com Phone: 6985793600.

Website: <a href="https://stchoud.github.io/">https://stchoud.github.io/</a> Military obligations: Fulfilled.

#### **SUMMARY**

My research areas of focus are network graph theory, machine learning, data science and cancer research. I have experience in network graph clustering, which includes building end-to-end machine learning pipelines, data curation, graph modeling, coding and testing. My work is implemented using Python and R. I have been instructing graduate students for 5 years, allowing me to further look into a plethora of mathematical fields and Python-based projects.

#### **EDUCATION**

2024-present PhD in Bioinformatics,

Thesis: "Cancer driver gene identification using machine learning"

Mathematics Research Center, Academy of Athens

Medical School of Athens, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Greece

2022 MS in Applied Mathematics, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Greece

Dissertation: "Network Graphs of Cancer Mutations" (https://pergamos.lib.uoa.gr/uoa/dl/object/3237319)

2020 **BS in Mathematics** National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Greece

## **FOREIGN LANGUAGES**

2013 English, level C2, ECPE, University of Michigan

2012 **Italian,** level B1, National Foreign Language Exam System

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

2020–present Online Tutoring, self-employed

2015–2021 **Ballroom Dance Instructor,** The Dance Club, Greece

#### **PRESENTATIONS**

06/2024 Principles of Machine Learning (presented at the Medical School of Athens, National and

*Kapodistrian University of Greece)* 

#### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

2020-present Online tutoring in graduate students from Greece and abroad. Examples of fields of

teaching include: Python programming, machine leaning algorithms, linear algebra,

probabilities, statistics, stochastic processes, calculus and linear programming.

## LIST OF PROJECTS (Last Updated 24/06/2024)

## PEER REVIEWED PAPERS

#### **Curriculum Vitae of Stamatis Choudalakis**

# **First Author**

1. **(Pre-print) S. Choudalakis**, G. A. Kastis, and N. Dikaios, "Intra-clustering analysis reveals tissue-specific mutational patterns".

(https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2024.02.26.582027v4)

# Co-Author

2. **S. Choudalakis**, M. Mitrouli, A. Polychronou, and P. Roupa, "Solving high-dimensional problems in statistical modelling: a comparative study," Mathematics, vol. 9, no. 15, p. 1806, 2021. (https://doi.org/10.3390/math9151806)